Japanese Film Ephemera Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Japanese film ephemera collection
1970-2014
MS 1905
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
9.5
(16 boxes)
The collection consists of handbills (chirashi), press kits, theater pamphlets, film newsletters, and catalogs that date from circa 1970 to the present. The collection documents over 600 contemporary Japanese directors and their films, as well as major film festivals and events in Japan. The bulk of the materials were generated in Japan and are in Japanese, however, some English-language publicity materials are included. The collection offers a substantial resource for researchers investigating contemporary Japanese film, as well as individual films and filmmakers.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Custodial History
Donated to the Yale East Asia Library by Fukuyama, Sanjiro; Fujita, Motohiko; Hori, Katsuyuki; Nakamoto, Rie; Tsuchimoto, Motoko; Yano, Kazuyuki; Yano, Shigeyuki; Yasuda, Takeshi.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by the East Asia Library, 2011.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of handbills (chirashi), press kits, theater pamphlets, film newsletters, and catalogs that date from circa 1970 to the present. The collection documents over 600 contemporary Japanese directors and their films, as well as major film festivals and events in Japan. The bulk of the materials were generated in Japan and are in Japanese, however, some English-language publicity materials are included. The collection offers a substantial resource for researchers investigating contemporary Japanese film, as well as individual films and filmmakers.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series: I. Directors and films, circa 1970-2009. II. Other film ephemera, 1975-2010.
Advertising fliers -- Japan; Motion picture actors and actresses -- Japan; Motion picture producers and directors -- Japan; Motion pictures -- Japan
- Directors and films, Circa 1970-2014; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  Series I consists of handbills, pamphlets, and press kits doumenting directors and their films.
  Arrangement
  The series is organized by director's name in the order of the Japanese syllabary. For each director's folder, if pamphlets and/or press kits are included, those materials are organized by title of film, also in the order of the Japanese syllabary. The director's name is indicated in both the Japanese vernacular and transliterated forms.
  - 青山真治 = Aoyama Shinji, 1999-2007 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Includes ユリイカ = Yuriika = Eureka
  - 秋原正俊 = Akihara Masatoshi, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 阿木耀子 = Aki Yōko, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 明比正行 = Akehi Masayuki, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Includes 1000年女王 = 1000-nen joō
  - 朝原雄三 = Asahara Yūzō, 1995-2008 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Includes 時の輝き = Toki no kagayaki
  - 麻生学 = Asō Manabu, 2000-2004 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Includes 千里眼 = Senrigan
  - 足立正生 = Adachi Masao, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 安達正軌 = Adachi Masaki, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - アベ ユーイチ = Abe Yūichi, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - アミノ テツロー = Amino Tetsurō, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Includes バツ＆テリー = Batsu & Terī = The Battery
  - 雨宮慶太 = Amemiya Keita, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Includes タオの月 = Tao no tsuki
  - マイケル アリアス = Michael Arias, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 安藤尋 = Andō Hiroshi, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 安藤真裕 = Andō Masahiro, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 庵野秀明 = Anno Hideaki, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Includes 新世紀エヴァンゲリオン劇場版：シト新生 = Shinseiki Evangerion gekijōban: Shito shinsei = Neongenesis Evangelion: death and rebirth; 新世紀エヴァンゲリオン劇場版：Air/まごころを、君に = Shinseiki Evangerion gekijōban: Air/Magokoro o, kimini = The end of Evangelion
  - 飯田譲治 = Iida Jōji, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Includes アナザヘヴン = Anaza hevun = Another heaven
  - 飯塚健 = Iizuka Ken, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - イ オンヒ = Yi On-hi, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 井川広太郎 = Igawa Kōtarō, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 井口昇 = Iguchi Noboru, 2005-2008 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 池田千尋 = Ikeda Chihiro, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 池谷薫 = Ikeya Kaoru, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 井坂聡 = Isaka Satoshi, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 石井かほり = Ishii Kaori, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 石井克人 = Ishii Katsuhito, 1998-2006 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 石井聰互 = Ishii Sōgo, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Includes 五条霊戦記 = Gojō reisenki = Gojoe
  - 石井隆 = Ishii Takashi, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 石井竜也 = Ishii Tatsuya, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Includes 河童 = Kappa
  - 石井康晴 = Ishii Yasuharu, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 石井良和 = Ishii Yoshikazu, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 石川北二 = Ishikawa Kitaji, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 石川均 = Ishikawa Hitoshi, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - 石川寛 = Ishikawa Hiroshi, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - 石田照 = Ishida Teru, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Includes 丹波哲郎の大霊界死んだらどうなる = Tanba Tetsurō no daireikai shindara dōnaru
  - 石原慎太郎 = Ishihara Shintarō, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Additional material (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 泉悦子 = Izumi Etsuko, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 和泉聖治 = Izumi Seiji, 1986-1991 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    Includes = On the road; 恋子の毎日 = Koiko no mainichi; シャイなあんちくしょう = Shai na anchikushō = Shy na anchikushou; 南へ走れ、海の道を！ = Minami e hashire, umi no michi o! = Run towards the south, on the road of the sea!; 極道渡世の素敵な面々 = Yakuza tosei no suteki na menmen.
  - いずみ よしはる = Izumi Yoshiharu, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 伊勢真一 = Ise Shin'ichi, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 磯村一路 = Isomura Itsumichi, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - 板倉真琴 = Itakura Makoto, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - 伊丹十三 = Itami Jūzō, 1984-1995 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    Includes あげまん = Ageman; お葬式 = Osōshiki; 静かな生活 = Shizukana seikatsu; ミンボーの女 = Minbō no onna; マルサの女 2 = Marusa no onna 2
  - 市川崑 = Ichikawa Kon, 1978-2008 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Includes どら平太 = Dora Heita; 火の鳥 = Hi no tori; 竹取物語 = Taketori monogatari; ビルマの竪琴 = Biruma no tategoto = The Burmese harp
  - 市川準 = Ichikawa Jun, 1987-2007 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Includes BU-SU = Busu; 竜馬の妻とその夫と愛人 = Ryōma no tsuma to sono otto to aijin = Ryoma's wife, her husband and her lover
  - 市川徹 = Ichikawa Tōru, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 一倉治雄 = Ichikura Haruo, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Includes またまたあぶない刑事 = Matamata abunai deka
  - 一瀬隆重 = Ichise Takashige, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 井土紀州 = Izuchi Kishū, 2003-2006 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 井筒和幸 = Izutsu Kazuyuki, 1983-2007 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Includes 二代目はクリスチャン = Nidaime wa kurisuchan; のど自慢 = Nodo jiman; 晴れ、ときどき殺人 = Hare, tokidoki satsujin; みゆき = Miyuki
    - Additional material, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 伊藤憲 = Itō Ken, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 伊藤俊也 = Itō Shunya, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 戌井市郎 = Inui Ichirō, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 犬童一心 = Inudō Isshin, 2007-2008 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 井上春生 = Inoue Haruo, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 井上泰治 = Inoue Yasuji, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 猪俣ユキ = Inomata Yuki, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 猪股隆一 = Inomata Ryūichi, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 今井和久 = Imai Kazuhisa, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 今泉光司 = Imaizumi Kōji, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 今井夏木 = Imai Natsuki, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - いまおか しんじ = Imaoka Shinji, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 今沢哲男 = Imazawa Tetsuo, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Includes Coo: 遠い海から来たクー = Kū: Tōi umi kara kita Kū
  - 今村昌平 = Imamura Shōhei, 1981-2008 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Includes ええじゃないか = Ējanaika
  - イ ユンギ = I Yun-ki, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - 入江悠 = Irie Yū, 2006-2008 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - 岩井俊二 = Iwai Shunji, 2006-2008 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - 岩田ユキ = Iwata Yuki, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - 岩名雅記 = Iwana Masaki, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 岩松了 = Iwamatsu Ryō, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Includes お墓と離婚 = Ohaka to rikon
  - 岩本仁志 = Iwamoto Hitoshi, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Includes 明日があるさ The Movie = Ashita ga arusa The Movie
  - 植岡喜晴 = Ueoka Yoshiharu, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - 内田英治 = Uchida Eiji, 2007-2009 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - 内田吐夢 = Uchida Tomu, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - 梅川俊明 = Umekawa Toshiaki, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    Includes 鯨捕りの海 = Kujiratori no umi = Whalers and the sea
  - 梅沢利之 = Umezawa Toshiyuki, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - ゴア ヴァービンスキー = Gore Verbinski, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    Includes ザ・リング = Za ringu = The ring
  - 榎戸耕史 = Enokido Kōji, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    Includes ふたりぼっち = Futaribocchi = Just two of us
  - ローランド エメリッヒ = Roland Emmerich, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    Includes ゴジラ = Gojira = Godzilla
  - 及川中 = Oikawa Ataru, 2007-2008 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - 大浦信行 = Ōura Nobuyuki, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - 大河原孝夫 = Ōkawara Takao, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    Includes 誘拐 = Yūkai = Abduction
  - 仰木豊 = Ōgi Yutaka, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - 大九明子 = Ōku Akiko, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - 大崎章 = Ōsaki Akira, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - 大嶋拓 = Ōshima Taku, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - 大島渚 = Ōshima Nagisa, 1983-1999 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    Includes 戦場のメリークリスマス = Senjō no Merī Kurisumasu = Merry Christmas Mr. Lawrence; 御法度 = Gohatto
  - 太田隆文 = Ōta Takafumi, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - 大谷健太郎 = Ōtani Kentarō, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 大津幸四郎 = Ōtsu Kōshirō, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - 大友克洋 = Ōtomo Katsuhiro, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 大西暢夫 = Ōnishi Nobuo, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 大仁田厚 = Ōnita Atsushi, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 大野伸介 = Ōno Shinsuke, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 大林宣彦 = Ōbayashi Nobuhiko, 1984-2004 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Includes 少年ケニヤ = Shōnen Keniya; 天国にいちばん近い島 = Tengoku ni ichiban chikai shima; 漂流教室 = Hyōryū kyōshitsu = The drifting classroom; 水の旅人 サムライキッズ = Mizu no tabibito samurai kizzu
  - 大宮エリー = Ōmiya Erī, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 大森一樹 = Ōmori Kazuki, 1984-2011 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Includes 恋する女たち = Koisuru onnatachi; シュート = Shūto!; すかんぴんウォーク = Sukanpin wōku; テイク・イット・イージー = Teiku itto ījī = Take it easy; ユー・ガッタ・チャンス = Yū gatta chansu = You gotta chance
  - 大森立嗣 = Ōmori Tatsushi, 2005-2013 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - スティーヴン オカザキ = Steven Okazaki, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 岡下慶仁 = Okashita Yoshihito, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 岡田主 = Okada Shū, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 岡部憲治 = Okabe Kenji, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 緒方明 = Ogata Akira, 2004-2014 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 小川王子 = Ogawa Ōji, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 小川和久 = Ogawa Kazuhisa, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 沖田修一 = Okita Shūichi, 2006-2011 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 荻上直子 = Ogigami Naoko, 2000-2012 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - 奥秀太郎 = Oku Shūtarō, 2007-2014 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - 奥田瑛二 = Okuda Eiji, 2004-2007 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - 奥原浩志 = Okuhara Hiroshi, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - 奥山和由 = Okuyama Kazuyoshi, 1994-1996 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Includes 大統領のクリスマスツリー = Daitōryō no Kurisumasu tsurī
  - 小栗康平 = Oguri Kōhei, 1990-2008 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Includes 死の棘 = Shi no toge; 眠る男 = Nemuru otoko
  - 押井守 = Oshii Mamoru, 2004-2010 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - 小田一生 = Oda Issei, 2005-2007 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - 小田和正 = Oda Kazumasa, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    Includes いつかどこかで = Itsuka dokokade = Sometime Somewhere
  - 落合正幸 = Ochiai Masayuki, 1997-1999 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    Includes 催眠 = サイミン = Saimin = Hypnosis; パラサイト・イヴ = Parasaito ivu = Parasite Eve
  - 小津安二郎 = Ozu Yasujirō, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - 呉美保 = Ō Miho, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - 恩地日出夫 = Onchi Hideo, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    Includes 地球へ = テラへ = Tera e = Toward the Terra
  - 甲斐田祐輔 = Kaida Yūsuke, 2004-2008 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - 柿本ケンサク = Kakimoto Kensaku, 2005-2007 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - 樫原辰郎 = Kashihara Tatsurō, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - 柏原寛司 = Kashiwabara Hiroshi, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - 片山修 = Katayama Osamu, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - 勝井千賀雄 = Katsui Chikao, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    Includes 北極のムーシカミーシカ = Hokkyoku no Mūshika Mīshika
  - 加藤治代 = Katō Chiyo, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - 門井肇 = Kadoi Hajime, 2006-2012 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - 角川春樹 = Kadokawa Haruki, 1982-1993 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    Includes 愛情物語 = Aijō monogatari; 天と地と = Ten to chi to = Heaven and earth; 汚れた英雄 The Last Hero = Yogoreta eiyū The last hero; Rex 恐竜物語 = Rex kyōryū monogatari
  - 門田龍太郎 = Kadota Ryūtarō, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    Includes 白き氷河の果てに Japan K2 Expedition 77 = Shiroki hyōga no hate ni Japan K2 Expedition 77
  - 金子功 = Kaneko Isao, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - 金子修介 = Kaneko Shūsuke, 1988-2009 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    Includes 恋に唄えば = Koi ni utaeba
  - 金子大志 = Kaneko Taishi, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - 金子文紀 = Kaneko Fuminori, 2003-2010 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    Includes 木更津キャッツアイ日本シリーズ = Kisarazu Kyattsu Ai Nihon shirīzu = Kisarazu Cat's Eye
  - 金子雅和 = Kaneko Masakazu, 2007-2010 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - 兼重淳 = Kaneshige Atsushi, 2007-2009 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - 金田敬 = Kaneda Satoshi, 2007-2011 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - 金丸雄一 = Kanemaru Yūichi, 2008-2009 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - 鎌仲ひとみ = Kamanaka Hitomi, 2003-2006 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - 亀井亨 = Kamei Tōru, 2006-2012 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - 河合勇人 = Kawai Takehito, 2007-2014 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - 河合義隆 = Kawai Yoshitaka, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    Includes 幕末青春グラフィティ Ronin 坂本竜馬 = Bakumatsu seishun gurafiti Ronin Sakamoto Ryōma
  - カワサキ キクオ = Kawasaki Kikuo, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Includes マイ・ロード = Mai rōdo = My road
  - 河崎実 = Kawasaki Minoru, 2006-2011 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 河崎義祐 = Kawasaki Yoshisuke, 1981-1983 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Includes グッドラックLove = Guddo rakku Love = Good luck Love; 天国のキッス プルメリアの伝説 = Tengoku no kissu Purumeria no densetsu; ブルージーンズメモリー = Burū Jīnzu memorī = Blue Jeans Memory
  - 川島透 = Kawashima Tōru, 1985-1987 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Includes TANTANたぬき = Tan tan tanuki; ハワイアンドリーム = Hawaian dorīmu = Hawaiian dream; 野蛮人のように = Yabanjin no yōni = Face it out
  - 河瀬直美 = Kawase Naomi, 1994-2011 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 川野浩司 = Kawano Kōji, 2006-2012 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 川村ケンスケ = Kawamura Kensuke, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 川村浩之 = Kawamura Hiroyuki, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 喜多一郎 = Kita Ichirō, 2005-2008 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 岸本司 = Kishimoto Tsukasa, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 北野武 = Kitano Takeshi, 2000-2008 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Includes Brother = Burazā; 座頭市 = Zatōichi = Zatoichi
  - 北村拓司 = Kitamura Takuji, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - 北村龍平 = Kitamura Ryūhei, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - 衣笠貞之助 = Kinugasa Teinosuke, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - 木下恵介 = Kinosita Keisuke, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Includes 衝動殺人 息子よ = Shōdō satsujin musuko yo
  - 木下雄介 = Kinoshita Yūsuke, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - 木下亮 = Kinoshita Ryō, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Includes 飛鳥へ そしてまだ見ぬ子へ = Asuka e soshite mada minu ko e
  - 金守珍 = Kim Sujin, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Includes 夜を賭けて = Yoru o kakete = Through the night; 夜を賭けて = Gamble the night
  - 木村威夫 = Kimura Takeo, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - 草野翔吾 = Kusano Shōgo, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - 草野陽花 = Kusano Yōka, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - 楠田泰之 = Kusuda Yasuyuki, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Includes パテオ = Pateo = Patio
  - 久世光彦 = Kuze Teruhiko, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Includes 自由な女神たち = Jiyū na megami tachi
  - 工藤栄一 = Kudō Eiichi, 1983-1991 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    Includes 泣きぼくろ = Nakibokuro; 逃がれの街 = Nogare no machi; 夜明けのランナー = Yoake no rannā
  - 窪田崇 = Kubota Takashi, 2006-2008 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - 熊井啓 = Kumai Kei, 1980-2007 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    Includes 海と毒薬 = Umi to dokuyaku = The sea and poison; 海は見ていた = Umi wa miteita = The sea watches; 天平の甍 = Tenpyō no iraka
  - 熊谷勲 = Kumagai Isao, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    Includes イーハトーブの赤い屋根 分校日記 = Īhatōbu no akai yane bunkō nikki
  - 熊谷博子 = Kumagai Hiroko, 1995-2006 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    Includes 三池 終わらない炭鉱の物語 = Miike owaranai yama no monogatari = Echoes from the Miike Mine
  - 熊切和嘉 = Kumakiri Kazuyoshi, 2006-2008 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - 熊坂出 = Kumasaka Izuru, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - 熊澤尚人 = Kumasawa Naoto, 2006-2009 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - 神代辰巳 = Kumashiro Tatsumi, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    Includes 恋文 = Koibumi
  - 蔵原惟繕 = Kurahara Koreyoshi, 1978-1991 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    Includes キタキツネ物語 = Kitakitsune monogatari = The fox in the quest of the northern sun; ストロベリーロード = Sutoroberī rōdo = Strawberry road; 南極物語 = Nankyoku monogatari = Antarctica
  - 栗原奈名子 = Kurihara Nanako, 1993-2008 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - 栗山富夫 = Kuriyama Tomio, 1989-1991 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    Includes 釣りバカ日誌2 = Tsuribaka nisshi 2; 釣りバカ日誌 4 = Tsuribaka nisshi 4
  - 黒木和雄 = Kuroki Kazuo, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - 黒澤明 = Kurosawa Akira, 1977-2010 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    Includes 影武者 = Kagemusha; 天国と地獄 = Tengoku to jigoku = High and low = The ransom; 夢 = Yume = Dreams; 乱 = Ran
  - 黒沢清 = Kurosawa Kiyoshi, 2002-2008 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    Includes アカルイミライ = Akarui mirai
  - 黒土三男 = Kurotsuchi Mitsuo, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    Includes オルゴール = Orugōru
  - 桑田佳祐 = Kuwata Keisuke, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Includes 稲村ジェーン = Inamura Jēn = Inamura Jane
  - 小池征人 = Koike Masato, 1993-2008 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Includes もうひとつの人生 = Mō hitotsu no jinsei
  - 小泉尭史 = Koizumi Takashi, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 小泉徳宏 = Koizumi Norihiro, 2006-2008 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 河野圭太 = Kōno Keita, 2006-2009 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 神山征二郎 = Kōyama Seijirō, 1992-2008 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Includes さくら = Sakura; 大河の一滴 = Taiga no itteki; 遠き落日 = Tōki rakujitsu; 宮沢賢治 その愛 = Miyazawa Kenji sono ai
  - 古川ロッパ = Kogawa Roppa, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Includes 古川ロッパとレビュー時代 モダン都市の歌・ダンス・笑い = Kogawa Roppa to rebyū jidai modan toshi no uta dansu warai
  - 小沼雄一 = Konuma Yūichi, 2006-2010 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 小原真史 = Kohara Masashi, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - 小林要 = Kobayashi Kaname, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - 小林正樹 = Kobayashi Masaki, 1975-2007 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - 小林政広 = Kobayashi Masahiro, 2006-2012 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - 小松隆志 = Komatsu Takashi, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - 是枝裕和 = Koreeda Hirokazu, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - 今敏 = Kon Satoshi, 2006-2007 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - 近藤明男 = Kondō Akio, 2007-2011 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - 合田経郎 = Gōda Tsuneo, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - 五島一浩 = Goshima Kazuhiro, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - 五社英雄 = Gosha Hideo, 1988-1991 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    Includes 陽炎 = Kagerō; 鬼龍院花子の生涯 = Kiryūin Hanako no shōgai; 肉体の門 = Nikutai no mon; 226 = Nī nī roku = The four days of snow and blood; 陽暉楼 = Yōkirō = Yohkiroh
  - 後藤憲治 = Gotō Kenji, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - 後藤俊夫 = Gotō Toshio, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    Includes イタズ = Itazu = Born wild, run free
  - 西條雅俊 = Saijō Masatoshi, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - 斎藤耕一 = Saitō Kōichi, 1979-2001 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    Includes 幸せを世界の友へ = Shiawase o sekai no tomo e
  - 斎藤貞郎 = Saitō Sadarō, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    Includes 子どものころ戦争があった = Kodomo no koro sensō ga atta
  - 斎藤孝 = Saitō Takashi, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - 斎藤光正 = Saitō Mitsumasa, 1979-1986 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    Includes 戦国自衛隊 = Sengoku jieitai; チェッカーズ Song for U.S.A. = Chekkāzu Song for U.S.A. = Checkers Song for U.S.A.; 積木くずし = Tsumiki kuzushi; ニッポン警視庁の恥といわれた二人組 刑事珍道中 = Nippon Keishichō no haji to iwareta futarigumi deka chindōchū
  - 崔洋一 = Sai Yōichi, 1988-2009 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    Includes バトルニューウェーブ・美少女バイオレンス「ASUKA」 花のあすか組！ = Batoru nyūwēbu bishōjo baiorensu hana no Asukagumi!
  - 三枝健起 = Saegusa Kenki, 1996-2009 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - 佐向大 = Sakō Dai, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - 坂口拓 = Sakaguchi Taku, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - 坂田雅子 = Sakata Masako, 2007-2011 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - 坂牧良太 = Sakamaki Ryōta, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - 阪本順治 = Sakamoto Junji, 1996-2011 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    Includes KT = KT, 魂萌え！ = Tama moe!; 亡国のイージス = Bōkoku no Ījisu; ぼくんち = Bokunchi
    - Additional material, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 坂元友介 = Sakamoto Yūsuke, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - 櫻井剛 = Sakurai Tsuyoshi, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - 櫻井雅章 = Sakurai Masaaki, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - 佐々木紳 = Sasaki Shin, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - 佐々木浩久 = Sasaki Hirohisa, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - 佐々木誠 = Sasaki Makoto, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - 笹部香 = Sasabe Kaoru, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - 佐々部清 = Sasabe Kiyoshi, 2004-2012 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - 貞永方久 = Sadanaga Masahisa, 1983-1996 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Includes 海嶺 = Kairei; 必殺！ = Hissatsu! = The Hissatsu; 必殺！ 主水死す = Hissatsu! Mondo shisu
  - 佐藤佐吉 = Satō Sakichi, 2005-2011 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 佐藤二朗 = Satō Jirō, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 佐藤純彌 = Satō Junya, 1977-1997 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Includes 植村直己物語 = Uemura Naomi monogatari; おろしや国酔夢譚 = Oroshiyakoku suimutan; 超能力者 未知への旅人 = Chōnōryokusha michi eno tabibito; 敦煌 = Tonkō = Dun-Huang, 人間の証明 = Ningen no shōmei; 北京原人 = Pekin genjin = Pekin-Genjin; 未完の対局 = Mikan no taikyoku; 野性の証明 = Yasei no shōmei
  - 佐藤徹也 = Satō Tetsuya, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - サトウ トシキ = Satō Toshiki, 2005-2013 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 佐藤太 = Satō Futoshi, 2007-2013 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 佐藤真 = Satō Makoto, 1992-2005 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Includes まひるのほし = Mahiru no hoshi
  - 佐藤雅道 = Satō Masamichi, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Includes いとしのエリー = Itoshi no Erī; はいからさんが通る = Haikara-san ga tōru
  - 佐藤祐市 = Satō Yūichi, 2006-2013 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 佐藤レオ = Satō Reo, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - 澤井信一郎 = Sawai Shinichirō, 1981-2007 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    Wの悲劇 = W no higeki = Tragedy of W; 野菊の墓 = Nogiku no haka
  - 澤田鎌作 = Sawada Kensaku, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - ケラリーノ サンドロヴィッチ = Kerarino Sandorovitchi, 2006-2008 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - 塩田明彦 = Shiota Akihiko, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - 七里圭 = Shichiri Kei, 2006-2007 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - 篠田正浩 = Shinoda Masahiro, 1979-2008 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    Includes 少年時代 = Shōnen Jidai; 瀬戸内少年野球団 = Setouchi shōnen yakyūdan; 近松門左衛門 鑓の権三 = Chikamatsu Monzaemon yari no gonza; 梟の城 = Fukurō no shiro = Owl's castle; 舞姫 = Maihime = Die Tänzerin; 夜叉ヶ池 = Yashagaike
  - 篠原哲雄 = Shinohara Tetsuo, 1993-2011 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    Includes 命 = Inochi
  - 柴田一成 = Shibata Issei, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - 柴田剛 = Shibata Gō, 2004-2009 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - 柴田昌平 = Shibata Shōhei, 2006-2010 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - 芝山努 = Shibayama Tsutomu, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    Includes がんばれ！！タブチくん！！ = Ganbare!! Tabuchi-kun!!; がんばれ！！タブチくん！！初笑い第三弾 ああツッパリ人生 = Ganbare!! Tabuchi-kun!! Hatsuwarai dai san-dan ā tsuppari jinsei; ドラえもん のび太のねじ巻き都市冒険記 = Doraemon Nobita no nejimaki shitī bōkenki; ザ・ドラえもんズ 怪盗ドラパン謎の挑戦状！ = Za Doraemonzu kaitō Dorapan nazo no chōsenjō
  - 島田角栄 = Shimada Kakuei, 2006-2010 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - 島田紳助 = Shimada Shinsuke, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    Includes 風、スローダウン = Kaze, surōdaun = Slow Down
  - 清水宏 = Shimizu Hiroshi, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - 清水崇 = Shimizu Takashi, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    Includes 呪怨 パンデミック = Juon pandemikku = Juon Pandemic = The Grudge 2
  - 下村勇二 = Shimomura Yūji, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - 下山天 = Shimoyama Ten, 2001-2009 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    Includes 弟切草 = Otogirisō
  - 生野慈朗 = Shōno Jirō, 1988-2008 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    Includes いこかもどろか = Ikoka modoroka
  - 白石晃士 = Shiraishi Kōji, 2006-2011 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - 白石康彦 = Shiraishi Yasuhiko, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - 白鳥哲 = Shiratori Tetsu, 2005-2007 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - 白羽弥仁 = Shiraha Mitsuhiro, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Shin = Shin, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - 新海誠 = Shinkai Makoto, 2007-2011 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - 新城卓 = Shinjō Taku, 1984-2007 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    Includes ザ・オーディション = Za ōdishon = The Audition
  - 実相寺昭雄 = Jissōji Akio, 1988-2006 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Includes 帝都物語 = Teito monogatari = Tokyo - The Last Megalopolis
  - 末永賢 = Suenaga Ken, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 周防正行 = Suō Masayuki, 2007-2011 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 須賀大観 = Suga Taikan, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 菅原浩志 = Sugawara Hiroshi, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 杉井ギサヴロー = Sugii Gisaburō, 1986-2011 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Includes ストリートファイター II Movie = Sutorīto faitā II movie = Street fighter 2 movie; タッチ = Tacchi = Touch; タッチ 2 さよならの贈り物 = Tacchi 2 Sayonara no okurimono = Touch 2; 紫式部源氏物語 = Murasaki Shikibu Genji monogatari = Murasaki Shikibu The Tale of Genji
  - 杉田成道 = Sugita Narimichi, 1988-1994 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Includes 優駿 = Orashion = Oraciòn; ラストソング = Rasuto songu = Last song
  - 杉村六郎 = Sugimura Rokurō, 1983-1984 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Includes 刑事物語 2 りんごの詩 = Keiji monogatari 2 ringo no uta; 刑事物語 3 潮騒の詩 = Keiji monogatari 3 shiosai no uta
  - 杉山卓 = Sugiyama Taku, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Includes 火の鳥 2772 愛のコスモゾーン = Hi no tori 2772 ai no kosumozōn = Phoenix 2772